A. SADIQUE BASHA

PROFILE

HEAD - SALES & MARKETING -SOFTWARE SALES OF ERP PAKAGE having more than 18 years of Overall experience with **15 years** in SOFTWARE SALES. I also have rich experience in SALES OF **ENGINEERING PRODUCTS** as a **SALES EXECUTIVE** until I stepped into IT. I have good Analytical skills and, I am keen in investigating the root cause of the task which has helped me find varying roles in the Job I have undertaken. I am looking for a more challenging job in SOFTWARE SALES that would help as a Window to learn and contribute more.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91 70100 13350

EMAIL:

sadiquemba.itsales@gmail.com

LINKEDIN PROFILE:

<u>linkedin.com/in/sadique-basha-</u> 913403193

WORK EXPERIENCE

- ASSISTANT VICE PRESIDENT SALES & MARKETING at TRST Score Pvt Ltd. (Feb 2022 – Till Date)
- 2. SALES HEAD INDIA at Techminds Group India Pvt Ltd (Sep 2019 Oct 2021)
- Worked as HEAD SALES & MARKETING for ERP Software Services with Entice Technologies India Pvt Ltd., (March 2013 – December 2016)
- 4. Worked as SR. SALES & MARKETING MANAGER ERP SOFTWARE SALES with Focus Softline Software Services Pvt Ltd, (Sep 2009 – Feb 2013)
- Served as BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER ERP SOFTWARE SALES for Logic Software Pvt. Ltd., (Oct 2006 – Aug 2009)
- Worked as MANAGER SALES ERP Software Sales at E-Softex India Pvt Ltd (Dec 2003 - Sep 2006)
- SALES EXECUTIVE at Rai Prexim (India) Pvt Ltd, ISO 9001
 Certified company (May 2001 Nov 2003)

1. TRST Score India Pvt Ltd.,

ASSISTANT VICE PRESIDENT – SALES 7 MARKETING at TRST Score Pvt Ltd. (Feb 2022 – Till Date)

2. TECHMINDS GROUP INDIA Pvt Ltd.

Techminds Group founded in 2007, headquartered in New Jersey, USA is a Global Information Technology Services firm known for our deep industry experience and high customer satisfaction with Delivery centre in Chennai India. Techminds Group is a NJFast50 winner (2016), Inc 5000 (2017) Winner, is one of the fastest growing private companies in America, Singapore, India and Middle East. also, a Microsoft Certified Partner focused on Data Management, Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP, CRM) and Azure platform solutions. Offer wide range of solutions, services that span across industries with guaranteed savings in efforts, cost without compromising on the quality. Our ISO and CMM Certified Global delivery centres backed up with business continuity plans that deliver unparalleled software solutions with 24x7 Support round the clock with Project Services, Managed Services and Consulting Services Offerings.

Designation : Sales Head – India

Product : Microsoft ERP, CRM, Microsoft Office Suites.

Experience : 2.2 Years.

Solutions we provide : ERP, CRM, BI, Web Designing, Project Services, Managed Services.

Role as Regional Sales Head - Pan India:

- Selling Microsoft Solutions Across India Microsoft ERP (Nav, Ax), D365 CRM, M365, Azure.
- New Business Development. Sells products by establishing contact and developing relationships with prospects; recommending solutions.
- Deliver prepared sales talks, reading from scripts that describe our company's products or services, in order to explain & thereby convince potential customers to purchase our products & services.
- Maintains relationships with clients by providing support, information, and guidance; researching and recommending new opportunities; recommending profit and service improvements.
- Identifies product improvements or new products by remaining current on industry trends, market activities, and competitors.
- Listening to customer requirements and presenting appropriately to make a sale.
- Acting as a contact between a company and its existing and potential markets.
- Negotiating the terms of an agreement and closing sales.

- Gathering market and customer information; gaining a clear understanding of customers' businesses and requirements.
- Organizing Team meeting and sharing best practice with colleagues.
- Heading Sales Team of BDM's and Executives.
- Strategizing to achieve quarterly, Half yearly and Annual Targets.

3. ENTICE TECHNOLOGIES

Entice Technologies is IT Managed Service Provider. Provide IT managed services and solutions that ensure minimizing downtime, increasing productivity and maximizing profits. Believe in Quality service and are committed to excellence. Products like ERP, CRM, SCM, BI Tools, Web Designing, Hardware and Servers. Sales and Support of Software and Hardware complete IT Solution for customers. These attributes have bonded us in a trustworthy relationship with our customers over a period. We ensure that our customers are comfortable and have total satisfaction with our services. For us the challenge is in gaining customers trust wherever they are.

Designation : Head - Sales & Marketing ERP Software Solution

Product : Software – ERP Pakage

Experience : 3.10 Years.

Solutions we provide : ERP, CRM, SCM, BI, Web Designing, Hardware and Servers.

Role as Head – Sales & Marketing in Entice Technologies:

- Prepares the annual Work Plan.
- Determine Sales Strategies quarterly, half yearly and annually.
- Managing Team of Managers and Executives.
- Lead team by identifying training needs.
- Define and follow up targets and objectives.
- Define Target for Managers and Executives.
- Key Person in Software Upgrade and Enhancements.
- Determine new opportunities by analyzing business needs.
- Generating leads & finding new prospects through different sources.
- Responsible for interacting with key persons in Industry for proper understanding of customer requirement, study the technical parameter, provide solutions and convert it into sales.
- Identify the key customer and maintain regular interaction and relationship for getting regular business
- To design a solution and making techno-commercial proposal

- Fundamental understanding of IT Solutions
- Industry analysis according to our services and solutions [Products what we are having]
- Strategic & tactical planning
- Follow up the customer according to their schedule
- Strong Customer Management skills and ability to meet the commitments
- Monitor and report on activities and provide relevant management information
- Internal CRM update for keeping track record of customers and prospects.

4. FOCUS SOFTWARE

The Focus Suite of advanced business applications has been evolving since 1992 and has enhanced business efficiency at more than 42,000 corporations across the globe. Conceived by a team of professionals focused on developing cost-efficient software solutions for specific industry requirements, the Focus Suite today stands for a wide range of comprehensive, versatile business management applications. For you, the Focus expertise enables production of customized solutions on short implementation cycles. We are presence in 15 countries 22 offices globally.

17 years of experience in developing holistic software, Focus has been providing best-fit answers to business questions for small mid and large-sized organizations across the world. Our solutions adapt to your business processes and not the other way around. To do business as usual with increased productivity and profit.

Designation : Sr.Sales & Marketing Manager – ERP Software Solution

Product : Software – ERP Package.

Experience : 3.6 Years.

Solutions we provide : ERP, CRM, SCM, WM, ARMS

Responsibilities as Sales & Marketing Manager in Focus Software:

- Managing a Team of Assistant Managers and Executives
- Generating leads & finding new prospects through different sources
- Responsible for interacting with key persons in Industry for proper understanding of customer requirement, study the technical parameter, provide solutions and convert it into sales.
- Identify the key customer and maintain regular interaction and relationship for getting regular business
- To design a solution and making techno-commercial proposal
- Fundamental understanding of IT Solutions
- Industry analysis according to our services and solutions [Products what we are having]

- Strategic & tactical planning
- Follow up the customer according to their schedule
- Strong Customer Management skills and ability to meet the commitments
- Monitor and report on activities and provide relevant management information
- Internal CRM update for keeping track record of customers and prospects
- Efficiency target meet.

5. LOGIC SOFTWARE

Logic Software is a fast-growing dynamic Software Development Organization with a Global Development Centre in Chandigarh and Branch Offices in all Major Cities of a Country. Company business activities include consultation, Software Development, Implementation & Support of ERP Software. They have been in this business for the last 16 years and today stand out as the largest software vendor in the region both in terms of organization structure and sale. The goal is to ensure that our clients derive maximum returns on their investments and remain competitive by implementing the best fit solutions.

Designation : Business Development Manager – ERP Software Solution

Product : Software – ERP Pakage

Experience : 2.11 Years

Solution : ERP, SCM, Retail ERP & CRM, POS

My Job Activities as Business Development Manager (South India Region):

- Business Origination Finding Deals through multiple Source
- Market Research / Analysis Market Demand and potentiality
- Manage the entire Sales Process Qualification, Pre-Sales, Demos, Pricing, Proposals, Negotiations and Closure.
- Marketing Product though Multiple Sources Cold Calls, E-Mail trigger etc
- Strategic planning for Marketing and Sales
- Understanding the Requirements of Clients & Positioning an appropriate Solution to them.
- Demonstrating the Product to Customers Ability to handle Corporate Presentations and Managing the Expectations of the Customers.
- Excellent Customer interaction skills, Communications and Presentation skills.
- Explaining Technical Info of Product to Clients and grab the requirements than interacting with Development Team for any Developments occur in some instance.
- Negotiation with Customers

- Marinating existing accounts and general accounts.
- Efficiently reached sales target.

6. E-SOFTEX SOFTWARE

E-Softex is a complete web solutions company specializing in the fields of Web Design and Development, Ecommerce Solutions, Web Application Development, Database Integration, Flash Development, Development of ERP Solutions for small and mid-size industries. Outsourcing and Search Engine Optimization Services with Development Centers in Pune, Bangalore, Chennai, Spain & UK.

Designation : Manager Sales – ERP Software Sales

Product : Software – ERP Package

Experience : 2.10 Years

Roles and Responsibilities as Mentioned in above companies.

DOMAIN EXPERIENCE

7. RAI PREXIM (INDIA) Pvt. Ltd,

Rai & Sons India Pvt. Ltd, Financially and Technically Collaborated with M/s Prexim Diesel spoil of Czech Republic formed a new company. Rai Prexim (India) Pvt. Ltd. Have been the Core Salesperson for one of the biggest OEM (Original Equipment Manufacturer) with clients who are the leading Manufacturers of Diesel Engines like VOLVO Penta of Sweden, SKODA (CKD) of Czech Republic & Deutch of Germany.

My Designation : Sales Executive

Product : Generator

Experience : 2.8 Years

My Roles & Responsibilities Includes:

- Maintain good relationship with customers and was a liaison between corporate office and the customers.
- Efficiently reached sales target.
- Marinating existing accounts and general accounts.
- Preparation of quotations, Negotiation and follow up for new orders as well as spares and services.
- Market Analysis and sales Information system.
- Presentation (Demonstration) of Product.

- Handling Corporate Sales.
- Organizing Promotion Campaigns.
- Fixing of targets, Inventory planning and Demand estimation.
- Achieving sales target.

EDUCATION

MBA - Master of Business Administration

Specialization in Marketing

Mohammed Sathak College of Arts and Science, Chennai (Affiliated to University of Madras)

BBA - Bachelor of Business Administration

At Mazhur-ul-uloom College, Ambur (Affiliated to University of Madras)

Academic Projects:

<u>M.B.A:</u> Completed my Dissertation project at **Hindustan Motors Mitsubishi Lancer**, Chennai on "Consumer Behavior with Premium Cars" for duration of 6 months.

B.B.A: Completed project at **M/S. N.M.Z. Group of Shoe Companies**, Ambur in Production Planning 2 months.

COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

Tools : MS Office Suite – Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Teams etc.

Accounting Packages : AAC – Advance Accounting Certification, Tally 5.4, 7, Tally ERP 9.

Software Package : Microsoft ERP (NAV,AX), Dynamics CRM, SAP R/3 SD Module V4.7

Focus ERP, Logic ERP

Personal Details

Gender/Age/marital status : MALE / 42 / UN-MARRIED

Passport : E 4534915

Email : sadiquemba.itsales@gmail.com

Phone : +91-70100 13350.
